

🛪 shin2suka.github.io | 🖸 shin2suka | 🛅 tianyu-shin-ren

Summary.

Current 2020 MMF Candidate at U of T. 2nd Place and Best Visualization in 2019 ASA DataFest Competition. Proficient in Python (Pytorch, Numpy, sk-learn, Pandas), R, SQL, MATLAB and Excel. Experienced in machine learning and deep learning. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools to apply in finance.

Education

Master of Mathematical Finance, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

CANDIDATE

Aug. 2019 – Present

• Relevant Course: Data Science; Pricing Theory; Stochastic Analysis; Volatility Modeling; Investment&Finance; Numerical Methods for Finance

Honours Bachelor of Science, University of Toronto, GPA: 3.88/4.0

Toronto, CA

APPLIED MATHEMATICS IN FINANCE (SPECIALIST), STATISTICS (MAJOR) AND COMPUTER SCIENCE (MINOR)

Sept. 2015 - Apr. 2019

- Relevant Course: Real Analysis; Numerical Methods; Stochastic Processes; Probability Theory; Multivariate Data Analysis, Time Series; Optimization; Machine Learning; Statistical Learning; Deep Learning; Databases
- Dean's List Scholar (Faculty of Arts and Science)
- New College Student Council In-Course Scholarship
- Student Ambassador, Department of Computer Science

Work Experience_

Teaching Assistant Toronto, CA

University of Toronto

Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Running tutorials, holding office hour and marking tests for a first-year Data Science course (STA130)
- Topics include: Data Visualization, Data Wrangling, Statistical Models and Machine Learning

Business Analyst Toronto, CA

SCOTIABANK, GLOBAL CAPITAL MARKET TECHNOLOGY, DERIVATIVES TRADING

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Working in the Market Data System and Risk & Valuation Team, responsible for IR Curve mapping, automation PV regression testing, Inflation Swap PV testing, IR curve analytic, date utility tools(date rolling)
- Designed and Implemented an internal website for BA automation testing using Python Flask, HTML, and JavaScript, functionalities include: login/logout, automation testing and displaying results through triggering Python scripts

Awards & Projects

COMPETITION

2019 **2nd Place & Best Visualization**, 2019 ASA DataFest at U of T

Toronto, CA

PROJECTS

2019 MNIST Handwritten Digits Recognition, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

2019 **CNN for Image Processing**, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

Extracurricular Activity_

Peer Mentor Toronto, CA

DEPARTMENT OF STATISTICAL SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Jan. 2018 – Apr. 2018

- Assisting students in overcoming obstacles of first year in university and providing support
- Organizing group meeting sessions monthly and discussing academic and career development

Student Project Team, Event Manager

Toronto, CA

RISKLAB, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Led a team to organize, promote and facilitate several large-scale professional events, topics including Risk Management, CFA, Big Data and FinTech
- Hosted Financial Data Case Competition by cooperating with RBC Data Analytics and proudly provided internship opportunities to the winners, where we had over 30 teams registered

August 29, 2019 Tianyu S. Ren · Résumé